Toshika Gharpande

toshikagharpande@gmail.com | +91 7028667231 | |Social -LinkedIn

Professional Summary

Business intelligence developer with 5.8 years of Experience in BI Development. Having complete knowledge of software development life cycle. Adaptive to challenging environment and a strong team player with project management skills. Looking forward to leverage my previous experience and technical skills, to gain understanding of business analysis process more deeply and the requirements for project planning.

Skills

Power BI, SQL, DAX, Data Visualization, Data Warehousing, Data Modeling, Microstartegy

Work Experience

Senior BI Engineer, Infosys (Recro)

Mobility Team(British Petroleum), Nov 2024 - till date

- Collaborated with Data modelers & Data Engineer to develop data models as required for creating the Power BI reports based on BP industrial mobile devices, connecting to various data sources (on-premises & cloud data sources, SharePoint, SQL, Excel) & importing relevant data performed data transformation, cleansing, and aggregation using Power Query and DAX language
- Defined and implemented dashboard security measures to protect sensitive data using Dynamic Row Level Security, implemented Drill-down & Drill-through Functionalities, Calculated columns & measures using DAX queries, bookmarks, custom tooltip, Filtering, reports using Power BI Desktop. Monitored and optimized dashboard performance to ensure a seamless user experience.
- End to End business analysis including conducting meetings with business users soliciting requirements and translating into technical requirements.

Senior BI Engineer, Brillio Technologies

Microsoft Enterprise Analytics, Jul 2023 - Oct 2024

- Proficiently utilized Power BI to create interactive and informative reports, Power BI dashboards & KPI scorecards from scratch for Dayforce and Microsoft Enterprise Analytics Project. POC on Paginated report for Finance data, ensured data quality, data accuracy by using SQL & consistency by implementing best practices.
- Implemented SQL queries for efficient data extraction and transformation.

Senior Data Engineer, Brillio Technologies

Xbox Marketing, Sep 2022 – June 2023

- Worked in Xbox Marketing Insights under gaming division of Microsoft, in the project, used Xbox Telemetry data from Cosmos
 big data warehouse to generate key Insights for marketing team to make key decisions like launching a new service or removal of
 an existing one targeting key customers who are at risk of churning out and many Xbox Console related analysis requests
 supporting all our marketing partners.
- Resolved and presented console, controller, Xbox user, Game play data, User Behavior, Analysis, Revenue, monetization and subscription-related queries and numbers for clients through SQL, excel, analytical skills and cosmos (scope).

Power BI Developer, Infocepts

Nielsen Consumer Insights, Feb 2020 – Aug 2022

- Worked for NielsenIQ Consumer insights to deliver market research and analysis on consumer behavior and business intelligence
- Provide detailed information, patterns in the form of Power BI Reports to understand about today's evolving consumers on the raw data gathered via Feedback Questionnaires, Reviews, Customer Sentiment Surveys, Behavioral Data, Social Listening.

MicroStrategy Developer, Infocepts

Nielsen Retail, Jul 2019 – Jan 2020

- Worked for US-based global marketing research firm and good domain knowledge about consumer behavior and marketing.
- Develop highly visual and interactive MicroStrategy Reports, Documents and Dossiers to support a large user base and Ad-Hoc queries as needed along with providing on-going analytical support.
- Worked on UI Path for automating requirement analysis and dossier development.

Education

Certifications

- PL-300
- Microsoft Power BI Desktop for business Intelligence
- UI path Certification
- Tableau Certification
- MicroStrategy Certified Specialist Analyst (MCSA)